Essam Mohamed Ahmed Mohamed



Personal Data

Date of birth:

September 12, 1984

Military service:

completed from 2005 to 2006

Driving license:

Third class driver's license

Social status:

Married, I have 3 children

Contact

Address:

Souk Algomaa Ellaban Alexandria.

Egypt

Phone:

- +2 (0)1206578929
- +2 (0)1012764870

Email:

esam.mohamed2008@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/esam-mohamed2008

Languages

Arabic - (Basic)

English - (V.G & Study in progress)

Russian – (Study in progress)

Summary

Network and information security specialist, cybersecurity specialist and web developer specializing in front end development. Experienced in all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Familiar with many programming languages including HTML5, PHP OOP, JavaScript, CSS, MySQL and Microsoft office business applications. Strong project management background and client relationship skills .

Highlights

- Network designer and specialist
- Project management
- Strong decision maker
- Java mobile application developer
- Cybersecurity

- Creative design
- Innovative
- Service-focused
- Information security
- Website developer in Java and HTML
- Website developer in css and python

Experience

- Head of Technology and Information Development Department,
 Tarradco Construction Contracting Company, from 2006 to 2010.
- Part-time lecturer (Arab Gate Institutes Princes Center NDP Educational Center) .
- Head of Accounts Department at Fastcall Tourism and Limousine Company (Tax Alex) from 2010 to 2013.
- Editor-in-chief and photographer for Monasabat Magazine in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, from 2013 to 2015.
- General Supervisor of Fastcall Tourism and Limousine Company (Tax Alex) from 2015 to 2016.
- General Secretary Bandar Al-Otaibi Foundation (real estate, contracting, elevators, home furniture and air conditioning) Riyadh, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia from 2016 to 2021.
- Freelance HTML, Css and Java web designer.

Education

- Industrial technician diploma above intermediate2003.
- Diploma of Cisco Network Academy 2009
- Bachelor of Higher Institute of Computer Science2010.
- Diploma in Information and Communication, Al Yamamah University, 2018

Certifications

- International Computer Driving License (ICDL).
- CCNA (Cisco Certified Network Associate).
- CCNP (Cisco Certified Network Professional).
- MCP (Microsoft Certified Professional).
- CompTIA+ Network Certificate.
- Network Security Certificate Course.
- Courses in digital marketing and via social media.
- HP Business Communication Operations Certification.
- Google Certificate of Fundamentals of Digital Marketing.
- Java Development SE Certification.
- Certificate of programming web pages using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Mobile app development certificate for Android system using a language Java.
- Certificate of Communication Operations at Work.
- HP Effective Leadership Certificate.
- HP Social Media Marketing Certificate.
- HP Data Presentation Certificate.
- HP Business Email Applications Certificate.



























































































